<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Sam Ghobril]]></title>
  <link href="http://samghobril.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://samghobril.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-13T19:44:45+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://samghobril.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sam Ghobril]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quoted: Creativity, Inc.]]></title>
    <link href="http://samghobril.github.io/blog/quoted-creativity/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-13T19:33:28+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://samghobril.github.io/blog/quoted-creativity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m more than halfway through Creativity, Inc. It&rsquo;s super inspirational, and Catmull&rsquo;s examples and thoughts are quite insightful. Here are three that I loved and saved into Quotebook:</p>

<!-- more -->


<blockquote>&#8220;Success convinces us that we are doing things the right way.&#8221;</blockquote>




<blockquote>&#8220;Most of us walk around thinking that our view is the best—probably because it is the only one we really knew.&#8221;</blockquote>




<blockquote>&#8220;When filmmakers, industrial designers, software designers, or people in any other creative profession merely cut up and reassemble what has come before, it gives the illusion of creativity, but it is craft without art.&#8221;</blockquote>


<p>All are quotes from Ed Catmull in Creativity, Inc.</p>

<p>Great read.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Typed: A Better Blogging Platform &rarr;]]></title>
    <link href="http://samghobril.github.io/blog/typed-a-better-blogging-platform/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-04T15:45:56+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://samghobril.github.io/blog/typed-a-better-blogging-platform</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>From the guys over at Realmac:</p>

<blockquote><p>Typed.com is a blogging service for writers, journalists, artists, storytellers, and for anyone with something to say. It’s the online writing platform that we’ve been wanting to create and use for years.</p></blockquote>

<p>Based on my experience, everything that Realmac have created has been incredibly well-crafted. They&rsquo;re my favorite software company, and I have no doubt that I&rsquo;ll be moving my blog to typed.com once it launches.</p>

<p>Check out the project, and definitely back it if you can.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quoted: The First Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://samghobril.github.io/blog/quoted-the-first-post/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-24T20:57:13+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://samghobril.github.io/blog/quoted-the-first-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I downloaded <a href="http://quotebookapp.com">Quotebook</a> when it first came out, then sort of forgot about it. Recently, however, I&rsquo;ve been using it more and more especially since I started reading again.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I decided to begin sharing some of my favorite quotes on this site every now and then. Here&rsquo;s three.</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Too often, we grab the hand and—without realizing it—walk off without the suitcase.&rdquo; — Ed Catmull in Creativity, Inc.</p></blockquote>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;When you&rsquo;re in your little room and you&rsquo;re working on something good but if it&rsquo;s really good you&rsquo;re gonna need a bigger room and when you&rsquo;re in the bigger room you might not know what to do you might have to think of how you got started sitting in your litle room.&rdquo; — The White Stripes in Little Room</p></blockquote>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;People like to listen to other people talking. That&rsquo;s the business plan.&rdquo; — Myke Hurley</p></blockquote>

<p>That last one&rsquo;s just great.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Balancing Entertainment]]></title>
    <link href="http://samghobril.github.io/blog/balancing-entertainment/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-19T18:00:53+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://samghobril.github.io/blog/balancing-entertainment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I do five main constant things for entertainment: Playing video games, listening to music, listening to podcasts, reading, and watching shows. I love all five, and don&rsquo;t intend on stopping any of them anytime soon. Here is how I balance my time between them.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Music</h2>

<p>Music is the easiest. I listen to music almost all the time, especially while studying and working. I can&rsquo;t bear doing any kind of work without some music in the background. I&rsquo;d delve into the kinds of music I listen to, but that&rsquo;s a topic for another post.</p>

<h2>TV Shows/Movies</h2>

<p>I usually keep movies for the weekends/evenings, and I watch them mostly with friends.
TV shows, on the other hand, are much harder to schedule. I&rsquo;ve been getting into Community recently, and I don&rsquo;t feel like I&rsquo;m really in control of how frequently I play an episode. TV shows can easily grow into an addiction, and it&rsquo;s something I&rsquo;m working on.</p>

<h2>Podcasts</h2>

<p>Podcasts are left for chores and commutes. When I&rsquo;m driving, cleaning up my desk, brushing my teeth, or any other similar activity, I&rsquo;m usually listening to a podcast.</p>

<h2>Video Games</h2>

<p>Video games are my main activity when I have scheduled breaks, mainly because they require time and attention more than most other activities. I really like immersing myself in my games, and I can&rsquo;t just sit down and play a console game for just 10 minutes and then turn it off. That&rsquo;s impossible for me.
It&rsquo;s worth noting that it&rsquo;s pretty different for mobile games. Mobile games are easy to pick up as well as put down. I also tend to listen to podcasts while playing games like Crossy Road or Super Hexagon, so that&rsquo;s efficient too.</p>

<h2>Books</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve got a <a href="http://www.samghobril.com/blog/new-years-resolutions/">new year&rsquo;s resolution</a> to read at least 10 books this year, so I&rsquo;ve been spending about 30 minutes every night reading a book. It&rsquo;s been great, and it has also been making my sleeping better; at least it feels like it.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>So yep, that &rsquo;s how I&rsquo;ve structured everything. Without this structure, I felt a bit lost whenever I had free time and ended up wasting it worrying about wasting my time (heh).
I still need to moderate my TV-watching, but I&rsquo;m pretty proud of how I spend most of my time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Overcast’s 2014 Sales Numbers &rarr;]]></title>
    <link href="http://samghobril.github.io/blog/overcasts-2014-sales-numbers/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-16T13:16:03+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://samghobril.github.io/blog/overcasts-2014-sales-numbers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>I can work in my nice home office, drink my fussy coffee, take a nap after lunch if I want to, and be present for my family as my kid grows up. That’s my definition of success.</p></blockquote>

<p>That&rsquo;s the lifestyle I&rsquo;m aiming for.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pixelated]]></title>
    <link href="http://samghobril.github.io/blog/pixelated/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-09T17:41:15+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://samghobril.github.io/blog/pixelated</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just launched my video series, Pixelated. It&rsquo;ll focus on app reviews and discussions, but could really go anywhere. I don&rsquo;t want to restrict myself to just one topic, and if I feel like discussing something new I definitely will.</p>

<p>Anyway, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Njcs9bFGMwA&amp;feature=youtu.be">give it a watch</a>. 😄</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Year's Resolutions]]></title>
    <link href="http://samghobril.github.io/blog/new-years-resolutions/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-04T18:41:58+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://samghobril.github.io/blog/new-years-resolutions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As 2015 came along, I made a small list of things that I&rsquo;d love to achieve this year, and I thought I&rsquo;d share it:</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>New App 1.0</h2>

<p>This hasn&rsquo;t been in development for a lot of time, but I&rsquo;m excited about it. I&rsquo;ll write more about it and maybe share a protoype video as it comes along.</p>

<h2>Start Video Series</h2>

<p>I had wanted to start a podcast for a while, but after watching <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tRofTIM1sP0">this video</a> by Dave Wiskus, I got a lot more excited about starting a video series. Work on the first episode has already started, and it should hopefully be out by next week.</p>

<h2>Mingle 2.0</h2>

<p>Not much information here, but this will probably be released after WWDC 2015. Probably for iOS 9.</p>

<h2>Read 10 books (minimum)</h2>

<p>I love reading, but realized that I barely read any books in 2014. I think 10 books would be great if I achieve that number, and I already begun with Ed Catmull&rsquo;s great Creativity, Inc.</p>

<h2>Blog at least once a week</h2>

<p>This is post #1 this year. 😄</p>

<h2>Excercise at least twice a week</h2>

<p>This will be the hardest. By far.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sketching It Out]]></title>
    <link href="http://samghobril.github.io/blog/sketching-it-out/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://samghobril.github.io/blog/sketching-it-out</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been spending the last few weeks trying decide what app to build. I&rsquo;ve already got a list of ideas that I&rsquo;d like to attempt, but the problem is choosing one.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>What I&rsquo;d usually do is this:</p>

<ul>
<li>Open up Xcode</li>
<li>Start building and prototyping the app idea</li>
<li>Decide to carry on with the idea or discard it</li>
</ul>


<p>This process worked, but it was tiresome. I have a little more than 40 Xcode projects that I&rsquo;ve started, and only 3 released apps on the App Store, which says a lot about this method.</p>

<p>So here&rsquo;s what I&rsquo;ve been doing: Sketching. I can get a pretty accurate idea about the app I&rsquo;m considering making by simply putting it out of my brain and onto a piece of paper. It&rsquo;s faster, easier to do, and much more satisfying.</p>

<p>An additional bonus is that I&rsquo;ll end up with a neat scrapbook of my ideas later on, which is much better than a folder full of barely-worked-on Xcode projects.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two Separate Thoughts on iPhone Sizes and the Apple Watch]]></title>
    <link href="http://samghobril.github.io/blog/two-separate-thoughts-on-iphone-sizes-and-the-apple-watch/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-16T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://samghobril.github.io/blog/two-separate-thoughts-on-iphone-sizes-and-the-apple-watch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Screen Sizes</h2>

<p>I’ve been thinking about the newly-announced screen sizes for the iPhone, and what that means for the iOS family. The 5s/5c are still sold today, but probably won’t be in the future. So does that mean that the 4” models would just disappear?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Here’s what I’m hoping for in the future:</p>

<ul>
<li>iPhone Mini: 4”</li>
<li>iPhone (Air?): 4.7”</li>
<li>iPhone Plus: 5.5”</li>
<li>iPad Mini: 7.9”</li>
<li>iPad Air: 9.7”</li>
<li>iPad Plus: 12.9”</li>
</ul>


<p>Many suggested that Apple didn’t release a 4” iPhone 6 due to technical limitations. If that’s the case, and I hope it is, then I really think Apple could consider bringing back the 4” model when it’s possible again.</p>

<p>On another note, on Debug 46, Vicki Murley suggested that the iPad Mini has no place anymore due to it being squeezed out by the sizes of the iPhone Plus and iPad Air. I actually think the current lineup works great. People with a 5.5” model would buy the iPad Air, while people with smaller models might still opt for the iPad Mini. I guess we’ll just have to wait and see what happens.</p>

<h2>Apple Watch and Notifications</h2>

<p>The Apple Watch got me thinking about the way notifications are dealt with. We’re extremely used to the idea of sound notifications. But, with the Apple Watch, how necessary are they? While wearing the Watch, we’re probably not going to miss any notifications, and we won’t need the sound to alert us if our iPhone isn’t nearby; the Watch is right there on our wrist.</p>

<p>And, what I’m also hoping for, is a smart, automatic way for sound notifications to get enabled/disabled on the iPhone. The Apple Watch could detect when it isn’t worn, and re-enable sounds when that happens. And vice versa.</p>

<p>This seems like a really minor detail, but it could potentially get us to stop thinking about the concept of putting phones on silent. I hope this exists.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cleaning Up Mingle's Code]]></title>
    <link href="http://samghobril.github.io/blog/cleaning-up-mingles-code/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-24T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://samghobril.github.io/blog/cleaning-up-mingles-code</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While working on Mingle’s 1.1 update, I’m noticing that some of its code is really cluttered. Some parts feel like they’re being held together by duct tape, and some other parts are just abnormally massive. This is because I learned a lot of stuff while working on Mingle. So before continuing work on the update, I’m going to work on cleaning up Mingle’s code.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I found this year-old <a href="http://www.objc.io/issue-1/lighter-view-controllers.html">article from objc.io</a> called Lighter View Controllers, and it looks like a great starting point. I love this piece of advice:</p>

<blockquote><p>One of the most powerful techniques to slim down your view controller is to take the UITableViewDataSource part of your code, and move it to its own class. If you do this more than once, you will start to see patterns and create reusable classes for this.</p></blockquote>

<p>I’d never thought about these kinds of things before. I’d always focus on getting a feature working, then moving on to the next one. The structure of the code was getting worse and worse, and I barely, if ever, took notice.</p>

<p>In order to make my work more enjoyable, I’m taking some time to clean things up. When things seem polished and clear, every problem will appear easier to solve.</p>

<p>It’s the equivalent of cleaning up my desk before studying. I’m glad I’m doing this.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Design and Content Consumption]]></title>
    <link href="http://samghobril.github.io/blog/design-and-content-consumption/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-17T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://samghobril.github.io/blog/design-and-content-consumption</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Supertop released <a href="http://castro.fm/">Castro</a> 1.1 about a week ago, and it really got me thinking about the relation between good design and the amount of content we consume.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I first thought about this when <a href="http://supertop.co/unread">Unread</a> came out. I had never used an RSS reader other than Feedly, and opening up the app, which feels really cluttered to me, made the content seem just as ugly and cluttered. It took a huge effort to get myself to read just a few articles, and I eventually just stopped. Unread, on the other hand, provided me with what could possibly be the most beautiful reading experience on iOS so far. I loved the typography, the structure, and the design of the app, and it got me reading and enjoying way more articles than before.</p>

<p>Castro had the same effect on me, which is even more interesting: podcasts aren’t even a visual form of media. I suppose when the packaging is this good, you want and need to know what’s inside. Many people argue that content is the only thing that matters, but I can’t be the only one who, still to this day, cringes at the sight of Reddit’s design.</p>

<p>I love good UI. I love beautiful designs. The simple, clean look of <a href="http://mattgemmell.com/">Matt Gemmell’s blog</a>, the new <a href="http://macstories.net/">MacStories</a> redesign, every single article on Unread; these are the things that push me to consume content, and that’s when content begins to matter. A restaurant could have the most delicious meals, but not one person would step in if it looked like a total mess. That’s the way it should be for everything. If you want to pull people in, give them the most beautiful entrance you can provide. That’s how they’ll know you care.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Releasing Mingle]]></title>
    <link href="http://samghobril.github.io/blog/releasing-mingle/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-04T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://samghobril.github.io/blog/releasing-mingle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On April 30th I released my first major iPhone app, Mingle. The feedback has been incredible, and the experience one-of-a-kind.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>About 30 minutes after announcing the release of Mingle on the App Store, Patrick Rhone published an amazing article on <a href="http://minimalmac.com/post/84327744289/as-much-of-an-advocate-as-i-am-for-using-the-built">Minimal Mac</a>. At that point, I got a great surge of excitement. Patrick really seemed to &ldquo;get&rdquo; Mingle, and that felt great.</p>

<p>Moments later, an article appeared on <a href="http://www.macstories.net/reviews/mingle-an-action-launcher-for-contacts/">MacStories</a> as well, which felt absolutely surreal. The app got reviewed on other sites too, including <a href="http://lifehacker.com/mingle-messages-contacts-across-networks-easily-1569855680/all">Lifehacker</a>, <a href="http://appadvice.com/review/hiddengem-mingle">AppAdvice</a>, <a href="http://www.geekswithjuniors.com/note/mingle-lets-you-launch-actions-from-your-contacts-list.html">GeeksWithJuniors</a>, and a few other. Seeing all these writers and bloggers whom I&rsquo;ve always followed take their time to write about <em>my</em> app stirred feelings that I&rsquo;ve never felt before inside me. It&rsquo;s humbling, to say the least.</p>

<p>However, this sort of feedback has had some drawbacks. I find myself more and more compelled to search for &ldquo;Mingle Contacts&rdquo; and &ldquo;Mingle App&rdquo; on Google and Twitter, searching for any kind of comments about the app. This kind of addiction has been really overwhelming, and really tough to overcome, at least for me. A day after release I even had &ldquo;Mingle Contacts&rdquo; as a saved search term on Tweetbot. I&rsquo;ve been trying to get past that, and forcing myself to stop from searching whenever I felt like it. It&rsquo;s getting better, and I suppose what I went through was a natural reaction to this kind of attention.</p>

<p>Ultimately, however, releasing Mingle has definitely been one of the most positive and enjoyable experiences of my life. There&rsquo;s nothing quite like seeing a large number of people really enjoy something you created, and I couldn&rsquo;t be more grateful.</p>

<p>To everyone who&rsquo;s used Mingle: thank you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Good Music]]></title>
    <link href="http://samghobril.github.io/blog/good-music/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-06T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://samghobril.github.io/blog/good-music</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A little less than a month ago, I downloaded Pharrell Williams&#8217; new album G I R L, and I had this to say:</p>

<blockquote><p>Admittedly @Pharrell&rsquo;s new album is a pretty fun record. So far, that&rsquo;s all it is though. It lacks any kind of innovation.</p>

<p>— @samghobril</p></blockquote>

<!-- more -->


<p>It really is a fun album. I enjoyed the upbeat, catchy riffs, and even now they can sound pretty entertaining, but the record hasn&rsquo;t provided me with anything other than short-lasting amusement.</p>

<p>Albums like Pharrell&rsquo;s make me skeptically excited, mostly knowing that the value of the album will soon fade, while albums like Arcade Fire&rsquo;s Reflektor make me curious about the contents of the album, the message behind every song, and make me feel that there&rsquo;s definitely more to the album than the effect of the first listen.</p>

<p>Good music builds my character, gives me a sense of understanding, and makes me think about the different perspectives that people have on life. It gives me the urge to inspect and really <em>concentrate</em> on the song, which causes it to get better the more I listen to it.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s the music I&rsquo;m looking for. I&rsquo;m looking for innovation, not earworms. I&rsquo;m looking for a lesson, a way of life, a feeling of introspection. I&rsquo;m looking for art.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
