<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Sam Ghobril]]></title>
  <link href="http://samghobril.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://samghobril.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-26T12:11:11+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://samghobril.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sam Ghobril]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sketching It Out]]></title>
    <link href="http://samghobril.github.io/blog/sketching-it-out/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://samghobril.github.io/blog/sketching-it-out</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been spending the last few weeks trying decide what app to build. I&rsquo;ve already got a list of ideas that I&rsquo;d like to attempt, but the problem is choosing one.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>What I&rsquo;d usually do is this:</p>

<ul>
<li>Open up Xcode</li>
<li>Start building and prototyping the app idea</li>
<li>Decide to carry on with the idea or discard it</li>
</ul>


<p>This process worked, but it was tiresome. I have a little more than 40 Xcode projects that I&rsquo;ve started, and only 3 released apps on the App Store, which says a lot about this method.</p>

<p>So here&rsquo;s what I&rsquo;ve been doing: Sketching. I can get a pretty accurate idea about the app I&rsquo;m considering making by simply putting it out of my brain and onto a piece of paper. It&rsquo;s faster, easier to do, and much more satisfying.</p>

<p>An additional bonus is that I&rsquo;ll end up with a neat scrapbook of my ideas later on, which is much better than a folder full of barely-worked-on Xcode projects.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Releasing Mingle]]></title>
    <link href="http://samghobril.github.io/blog/releasing-mingle/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-04T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://samghobril.github.io/blog/releasing-mingle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On April 30th I released my first major iPhone app, Mingle. The feedback has been incredible, and the experience one-of-a-kind.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>About 30 minutes after announcing the release of Mingle on the App Store, Patrick Rhone published an amazing article on <a href="http://minimalmac.com/post/84327744289/as-much-of-an-advocate-as-i-am-for-using-the-built">Minimal Mac</a>. At that point, I got a great surge of excitement. Patrick really seemed to &ldquo;get&rdquo; Mingle, and that felt great.</p>

<p>Moments later, an article appeared on <a href="http://www.macstories.net/reviews/mingle-an-action-launcher-for-contacts/">MacStories</a> as well, which felt absolutely surreal. The app got reviewed on other sites too, including <a href="http://lifehacker.com/mingle-messages-contacts-across-networks-easily-1569855680/all">Lifehacker</a>, <a href="http://appadvice.com/review/hiddengem-mingle">AppAdvice</a>, <a href="http://www.geekswithjuniors.com/note/mingle-lets-you-launch-actions-from-your-contacts-list.html">GeeksWithJuniors</a>, and a few other. Seeing all these writers and bloggers whom I&rsquo;ve always followed take their time to write about <em>my</em> app stirred feelings that I&rsquo;ve never felt before inside me. It&rsquo;s humbling, to say the least.</p>

<p>However, this sort of feedback has had some drawbacks. I find myself more and more compelled to search for &ldquo;Mingle Contacts&rdquo; and &ldquo;Mingle App&rdquo; on Google and Twitter, searching for any kind of comments about the app. This kind of addiction has been really overwhelming, and really tough to overcome, at least for me. A day after release I even had &ldquo;Mingle Contacts&rdquo; as a saved search term on Tweetbot. I&rsquo;ve been trying to get past that, and forcing myself to stop from searching whenever I felt like it. It&rsquo;s getting better, and I suppose what I went through was a natural reaction to this kind of attention.</p>

<p>Ultimately, however, releasing Mingle has definitely been one of the most positive and enjoyable experiences of my life. There&rsquo;s nothing quite like seeing a large number of people really enjoy something you created, and I couldn&rsquo;t be more grateful.</p>

<p>To everyone who&rsquo;s used Mingle: thank you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
